## **Matthew Lowe**

Software/Web Developer

## **Overview**

Over 10 years of experience, working on front and back end of projects. I am well versed in Git and doing code reviews, PRs and more on GitHub. I have worked with JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Python, SQL, APIs and more. Worked on frameworks such as React & Angular as well as Laravel & Cake PHP. I can work, learn, and articulate ideas well with others.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Freelance**

#### 2024 - Current

### Developer

- I was hired before I finished college and stared working the day after I graduated, I had never not been working full-time,
- Gave myself a break to foucs on myself, family, and health but I
  am not excited to look for new opportunities in my career
- Developed the front-end of a SaaS application that passed sensitive medical data to patients, nurses, and doctors
- Optimized database structures using normalization (1NF-5NF) for safe, scalable and eliminates redundancies
- Made coding interesting and exciting again by working on a variety of projects, from front-end, back-end, design work

### ShipEarly

### 2023 - 2024

### Full Stack Developer

- Small company contract role to work on the front and back end of their B2B application.
- Worked on the front end with javascript and helped with design.
- Worked on their back end using Cake 2 PHP to develop a sales system that integrated with salesforce.
- Worked with Git, did code reviews and integrated it with Trello
- While I was new and learning the codebase for myself, I oversaw teaching an employee the codebase and general coding practices as well.

### Quillsoft

2017 - 2023

Full Stack Developer

- Created and oversaw growth of the CRM system to ensure our tech team had all the data required to properly assist all our users.
- Built a PWA of our main desktop application which has become one of our main apps sold to schools.
- I developed a license management system that are integrated into all our applications and programs.
- Implemented the most up to date encryption methods to keep data secure

#### **Strategic Transitions**

2014 - 2017

<u>Developer</u>

- Created and license management system and integrated it into web applications and desktop programs.
- I created the encryption to keep the user's data secure.
- Developed a customized CMS system from scratch to allow for quick changes of content on the website.
- Wireframed, designed, and coded all the company's websites.

**NeXsys** 

2013 (Summer job)

**BPMS Administrator** 

- I created and oversaw the license management system and integrated it into our web and desktop applications.
- I created encryption for the user's data security.
- Developed a customized CMS system from scratch to allow for quick changes of content on the website.
- Wireframed, designed, and coded all the company's websites.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Fanshawe College**

2010 - 2013

Interactive Media & Design

- The first 2 years did a mix of coding, 2D/3D video, animation, and graphic design which focused on website design.
- Final year you could choose to focus on coding, video or 3D design and animation I chose coding.
- Our final project was with Strategic Transitions, and I was offered a job from them before I finished school.
- Took one year of Graphic Design before switching to this course that wasn't right for me, but I finished the year and learned a lot

#### Courses

I am constantly working to improve my overall knowledge and skillset as a developer. I most recently completed a React 2024 course on Udemy and I am currently working on a Google course on python that comes with a google career certificate once completed.

#### **SKILLS**

Outgoing / Self-Driven / Accountable / Independant / Proactively identify new tasks / Collaborating with colleagues

**References Available Upon Request**